# **Roston Sylvester Pereira**

A versatile IT professional with 5+ years of experience in software development, who can think out of the box, and bring a diverse skillset and creative drive to software application development. Strong experience in object-oriented programming, with attention to detail. Supportive and enthusiastic team player, dedicated to streamlining processes and efficiently resolving project issues.

Address: London, Ontario, Canada

E-mail: rostonpereira17@gmail.com

Website: <a href="https://rostonpereira.github.io">https://rostonpereira.github.io</a>

GitHub: https://github.com/RostonPereira

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/RostonPereira

#### **SKILLS**

C# | ASP.NET MVC 5 | HTML 5 | CSS 3 | Bootstrap 4 | JavaScript | SQL | Crystal Reports | Git | Web API | SDLC | JAVA | C++ | Android Dev | SQL Server | MySQL | MongoDB | SQLite

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Senior Executive (Software Development) Reliance Life Sciences Pvt. Ltd. – Navi Mumbai, India

January 2017 to April 2020

Reliance Life Sciences Pvt Ltd is a part of Reliance Industries Limited, a global Fortune 500 company, which deals with research and manufacturing of biotherapeutics, regenerative medicine, and molecular medicine.

- Led a cross-functional team of software engineers and designers to successfully develop and implement the website of Reliance Life Sciences Pvt. Ltd. using ASP.NET.
- Collaborated closely with stakeholders at Reliance Life Sciences to design, develop, and implement ASP.NET software applications used by internal teams including Manufacturing and Marketing.
- Co-ordinated with technical solution providers and business stakeholders throughout the SDLC to implement GxP critical software applications at Reliance Life Sciences.
- Responsible for modifying and maintaining existing ASP.NET software applications as per stakeholder requirements.
- Liaised with stakeholders for requirement gathering, and to create documentation throughout the SDLC.
- Provided functional and administrative support for software applications.
- Conducted training sessions for large groups of users to get them acquainted with the above applications.

# Software Development Engineer

February 2015 to January 2017

# RNM Moving Pictures Pvt. Ltd. - Mumbai, India

RNM Moving Pictures Pvt. Ltd. is a media production company that provides a Bollywood celebrity-backed online dance lessons and fitness platform (Dance with Madhuri).

- Successfully designed and implemented the <u>website of RNM Moving Pictures Pvt. Ltd.</u> using jQuery, HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap 4, and deployed on AWS Cloud.
- Led a cross-functional team of Software Engineers, Graphic Designers, and Video Editors to develop, implement, and launch the Dance with Madhuri (DWM) Android app. The app was downloaded and actively used by over 200K subscribers at the time. It was built using Android Studio and Java.
- Led the above team to launch the <u>Dance with Madhuri (DWM) website</u> using ASP.NET and MongoDB.
- Successfully designed and developed a key operational dashboard in Java by integrating data from multiple API sources including Google Play Store and Apple App Store. Metrics included active user info, returning

user info, platform utilization, etc.

- Managed and maintained the DWM website on Amazon Web Services Cloud infrastructure.
- Responsible for modifying and maintaining the website and Android app of DWM, including pushes to the Google Play Store.
- Provided functional and administrative support for the above products.

#### **EDUCATION**

# • Master of Science (MSc): Advanced Computer Science

2014

Department of Computer Science and Electronic Engineering | University of Essex, UK

# • Bachelors of Science (BSc): Information Technology

2013

St. Andrew's College of Arts, Science and Commerce | University of Mumbai, India

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

# Checkers Game | University of Essex

2014

- Led the team, and managed the documentation of SDLC.
- Collaborated with team members to develop the UI of the game, using Java.

# Who wants to be a Millionaire | University of Essex

2013 - 2014

• Successfully built an android app based on the TV game show "Who wants to be a Millionaire."

#### R-RunapP | University of Essex

2013 - 2104

• Successfully devised and created a fitness app that helps people stay fit, by measuring the calories burned and motivating them. The app also consisted of some inbuilt features like GPS navigation, Music player, and distress button.

## Volcania Automobiles | St Andrew's College of Arts, Science and Commerce

2013

• Successfully designed and implemented a website for automobile dealer, using ASP.NET and SQL Server 2008.

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

### Student Representative | University of Essex

2013 - 2014

- As a student representative, I attended staff-student liaison committee meetings.
- Raised academic issues concerning the students.

# Student Switch off Ambassador | University of Essex

2013 - 2014

• Created awareness on optimum use of resources, such as water and electricity, among university students.

#### **Volunteer | University of Essex**

2013 - 2014

• Created awareness about clean and healthy environment among school students.

## Volunteer | Garbage concern NGO

2011

- Organised a clean-up drive campaign along with an NGO.
- Scripted and acted in a play that conveyed the message of a clean and healthy environment.